<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-01-15T23:48:58-05:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">the Cyberian</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Srila Bhakti Kusum Sraman Goswami Maharaja</title><link href="/life_stories/2021/01/15/Maharaj.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Srila Bhakti Kusum Sraman Goswami Maharaja" /><published>2021-01-15T22:42:43-05:00</published><updated>2021-01-15T22:42:43-05:00</updated><id>/life_stories/2021/01/15/Maharaj</id><content type="html" xml:base="/life_stories/2021/01/15/Maharaj.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;srila-bhakti-kusum-sraman-goswami-maharaja&quot;&gt;Srila Bhakti Kusum Sraman Goswami Maharaja&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sri-sri-guru-gaurangau-jayatah&quot;&gt;Sri Sri Guru Gaurangau Jayatah&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After graduating from Dhaka Mitford Medical School as a medical doctor, he came to Prabhupada Srila Sarasvati Thakura and received mantra diksa and Sri Harinama and started serving the devotees in Sri Mayapur as advised by his Gurudev.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had exhibited extreme tolerance and possessed the greatest humbleness, emphasizing “trinadapi sunicena” and merged into the worship of Sri Harinama continually. He remained unaffected by the nuances caused by a small group of  so-called god-nephews. Even being the president and Acharya of Sri Chaitanya Math, he gracefully signed on papers brought in by some of those god-nephews stating, “my disciples will have no authority in managing and directing the services of the Math in the future.” When inquired by his disciples as to where they will live in the future, Srila Maharaja assured that if they continue to engage in  service, Sri Krishna Himself will provide them with shelter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/srila_guru_maharaja.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;srila_guru_maharaja.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Srila Bhakti Kusum Sraman Goswami Maharaja&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Image - Srila Bhakti Kusum Sraman Goswami Maharaja&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If any resident would come to complain about another  resident, Srila Maharaj would say “you are aatma, how come any words or deeds towards your body or mind would affect you?”, quoting “nainam chindanti sastrani…” His own response to external disturbances toward himself was to surrender to Sri Krishna and continue to chant Sri Harinama.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One resident had offended Srila Maharaja by cursing loudly using foul words. Maharaja was silent on this and continued his chanting. Noticing that Maharaja was not objecting or responding, this resident became louder and ultimately raised shoes toward Srila Maharaja. After three days, while the offender was maliciously engaged in  offensive talks with others, a ferocious snake fell on his head and bit him causing immediate death. Srila Maharaja prayed for forgiveness for and on behalf of the offender with a melted heart. This reminds us of Namacharya Sri Haridas Thakura.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What to speak of us, even heavenly demigods do not recognize a Vaishnava: “vaishnava cinite nare devera sakati”. We see an external appearance of a Vaishnava through our material senses and experiences. However only the Vaishnavas may  recognize each other.  The best of the Vaishnavas, Sri Shivji, had once sent in his own devotees, a shaiva couple, advising to accept shelter at the feet of Srila Sraman Goswami Maharaja. In another occasion, Shivji, Tarakeswar, had directed a person suffering from a disease, to get Srila Maharaja’s feet-water for his cure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Srila Bhakti Kusum Sraman Goswami Maharaja established Sri Giri Govardhan at Sri Chaitanya Math in Sri Mayapur to fulfill his Gurudeva’s desire and  paved the path around Sri Radhakund and Sri Shyamkund. He appeared on the day of Sri Govardhan puja and got bhajan-samadhi on the bank of Sri Radhakund in Sri Mayapur on Moksada ekadashi.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>admin</name></author><category term="life_stories" /><summary type="html">Srila Bhakti Kusum Sraman Goswami Maharaja</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jivani</title><link href="/life_stories/2021/01/15/life-stories.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jivani" /><published>2021-01-15T22:42:43-05:00</published><updated>2021-01-15T22:42:43-05:00</updated><id>/life_stories/2021/01/15/life-stories</id><content type="html" xml:base="/life_stories/2021/01/15/life-stories.html"></content><author><name></name></author><category term="life_stories" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="/jekyll/update/2021/01/15/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2021-01-15T22:42:43-05:00</published><updated>2021-01-15T22:42:43-05:00</updated><id>/jekyll/update/2021/01/15/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="/jekyll/update/2021/01/15/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll requires blog post files to be named according to the following format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YEAR-MONTH-DAY-title.MARKUP&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YEAR&lt;/code&gt; is a four-digit number, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MONTH&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DAY&lt;/code&gt; are both two-digit numbers, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MARKUP&lt;/code&gt; is the file extension representing the format used in the file. After that, include the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary></entry></feed>