<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-01-20T01:07:46-05:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Vinod Vani</title><subtitle>We are managing this blog post to upload the message of Prabhupada Srila Bhakti Siddhanta Sarasvati Thakur. And also will be adding life stories of Gaudiya Vaishnavs.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Srila Bhakti Saranga Goswami Maharaja</title><link href="/life_stories/Srila-Bhakti-Saranga-Goswami-Maharaja" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Srila Bhakti Saranga Goswami Maharaja" /><published>2021-01-19T21:49:43-05:00</published><updated>2021-01-19T21:49:43-05:00</updated><id>/life_stories/Srila-Bhakti-Saranga-Goswami-Maharaja</id><content type="html" xml:base="/life_stories/Srila-Bhakti-Saranga-Goswami-Maharaja">&lt;p&gt;In 1919, Srila Maharaja was initiated by Prabhupada Srila Sarasvati Thakura and was named as Sri Aprakrita Bhakti Saranga Goswami Prabhu. At the age of 32 years, he resigned from his job and came to Srila Prabhupada and submitted himself, and offered all his earnings and savings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…
Once Srila Goswami Maharaja was very sick with high fever and he slept mostly unconscious. In the morning he saw Sri Gurudeva Srila Prabhupada was putting wet-strip on his forehead and fanning to reduce fever. He learned that Sri Gurudeva has been sitting up and was taking care of him for two consecutive nights. Knowing this he became very uncomfortable and apologetic. Srila Maharaja paid obeisances and expressed his gratitude. Srila Prabhupada replied affectionately as “I have enormous hope that you will be performing wonderful services.  No one else in your place can do so. Sri Gaurhari has brought you in.  After losing you, I was feeling very helpless. Sri Gaur Sundar is very merciful, so He brought you back in.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The audience in London wanted to have darshan of transcendental form of Sri Krishna. This was obvious as the previous preachers had presented the formless conception of the Godhead. Srila Goswami Maharaja wanted five days’ time and he was searching for a diety of Sri Krishna since he only had Gomati and Govardhan Shila with him. In the following nights he dreamed of his Sri Gurudeva and he also saw Sri Krishna form within the Shila. He anxiously prayed for Saccidanda Vigraha. On the third night he dreamed that a wonderful Vasudev diety is present under a palm tree in the Sington garden. After getting up early in the morning, he went to that garden and recovered and brought in the Four-handed Vishnu diety and started His worship. That was in August 1937. In the next assembly under the chairmanship of lord Jetland, Srila Maharaja had presented the diety to the entire audience as per his previous promise.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="life_stories" /><summary type="html">In 1919, Srila Maharaja was initiated by Prabhupada Srila Sarasvati Thakura and was named as Sri Aprakrita Bhakti Saranga Goswami Prabhu. At the age of 32 years, he resigned from his job and came to Srila Prabhupada and submitted himself, and offered all his earnings and savings.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">परतंत्र जीव की स्वतंत्रता कहाँ से आयी?</title><link href="/upadeshamrit/from-where-freedom-has-come" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="परतंत्र जीव की स्वतंत्रता कहाँ से आयी?" /><published>2021-01-19T21:49:43-05:00</published><updated>2021-01-19T21:49:43-05:00</updated><id>/upadeshamrit/from-where-freedom-has-come</id><content type="html" xml:base="/upadeshamrit/from-where-freedom-has-come">&lt;p&gt;हमलोग सर्वतंत्र स्वतंत्र भगवान के अणु चिदंश हैं । इसीलिए पूर्ण वस्तु भगवान के गुण हममें अणुमात्रा में पूर्णस्वतंत्रता है तथा जीव में आंशिकरूप में स्वतंत्रता है । विमुखता दो प्रकार की हो सकती है- भोगोन्मुखी तथा त्यागोन्मुरवी । पथ दो हैं - एक जड़विलास का पथ तथा दूसरा चिद्विलास का पथ । कोई भी व्यक्ति निरपेक्ष या तटस्थ अवस्था में स्थित नहीं रह सकता । वह या तो भोगों की ओर , नहीं तो भगवान की सेवा की ओर जाता है । &lt;br&gt;

यदि सब समय भजन किया जाये , तो माया का आवरण नहीं रह सकता । भजन सब समय होना चाहिए । भजन में किसी प्रकार का छिद्र या दोष होने पर वहीं से उसी छिद्र या दोष का आश्रयकर माया हमें विपत्ति में डाल देती है । 
 &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Prabhupada Srila Bhakti Siddhanta Sarasvati Thakur</name></author><category term="upadeshamrit" /><summary type="html">हमलोग सर्वतंत्र स्वतंत्र भगवान के अणु चिदंश हैं । इसीलिए पूर्ण वस्तु भगवान के गुण हममें अणुमात्रा में पूर्णस्वतंत्रता है तथा जीव में आंशिकरूप में स्वतंत्रता है । विमुखता दो प्रकार की हो सकती है- भोगोन्मुखी तथा त्यागोन्मुरवी । पथ दो हैं - एक जड़विलास का पथ तथा दूसरा चिद्विलास का पथ । कोई भी व्यक्ति निरपेक्ष या तटस्थ अवस्था में स्थित नहीं रह सकता । वह या तो भोगों की ओर , नहीं तो भगवान की सेवा की ओर जाता है ।</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">आचार्य कौन है ?</title><link href="/upadeshamrit/who-is-archarya" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="आचार्य कौन है ?" /><published>2021-01-19T21:49:43-05:00</published><updated>2021-01-19T21:49:43-05:00</updated><id>/upadeshamrit/who-is-archarya</id><content type="html" xml:base="/upadeshamrit/who-is-archarya">&lt;p&gt;आचार एवं प्रचार - परायण भगवद्भक्त ही आचार्य हैं। आचार्य निरपेक्ष तथा मुक्त होते हैं। वे स्वयं सम्पूर्णरूप से असत्संग त्याग तथा निरन्तर कृष्णचर्चा का महान् आदर्श दिखलाते हैं। जो निर्भीक तथा निरपेक्षरूप से सभी को असत्संग त्याग की बात कहकर उनका असत्संग छुड़ा सकते हैं, वे ही आचार्य हैं। &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;यदि प्राण न दिया जाये, तो प्रचार नहीं हो सकता। &lt;b&gt;जो प्राण दे सकते हैं, वे ही प्रचार कर सकते हैं।&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Prabhupada Srila Bhakti Siddhanta Sarasvati Thakur</name></author><category term="upadeshamrit" /><summary type="html">आचार एवं प्रचार - परायण भगवद्भक्त ही आचार्य हैं। आचार्य निरपेक्ष तथा मुक्त होते हैं। वे स्वयं सम्पूर्णरूप से असत्संग त्याग तथा निरन्तर कृष्णचर्चा का महान् आदर्श दिखलाते हैं। जो निर्भीक तथा निरपेक्षरूप से सभी को असत्संग त्याग की बात कहकर उनका असत्संग छुड़ा सकते हैं, वे ही आचार्य हैं।</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Srila Bhakti Kusum Sraman Goswami Maharaja</title><link href="/life_stories/Srila-Bhakti-Kusum-Sraman-Goswami-Maharaja" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Srila Bhakti Kusum Sraman Goswami Maharaja" /><published>2021-01-19T20:49:43-05:00</published><updated>2021-01-19T20:49:43-05:00</updated><id>/life_stories/Srila-Bhakti-Kusum-Sraman-Goswami-Maharaja</id><content type="html" xml:base="/life_stories/Srila-Bhakti-Kusum-Sraman-Goswami-Maharaja">&lt;p&gt;After graduating from Dhaka Mitford Medical School as a medical doctor, he came to Prabhupada Srila Sarasvati Thakura and received mantra diksa and Sri Harinama and started serving the devotees in Sri Mayapur as advised by his Gurudev.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had exhibited extreme tolerance and possessed the greatest humbleness, emphasizing “trinadapi sunicena” and merged into the worship of Sri Harinama continually. He remained unaffected by the nuances caused by a small group of  so-called god-nephews. Even being the president and Acharya of Sri Chaitanya Math, he gracefully signed on papers brought in by some of those god-nephews stating, “my disciples will have no authority in managing and directing the services of the Math in the future.” When inquired by his disciples as to where they will live in the future, Srila Maharaja assured that if they continue to engage in  service, Sri Krishna Himself will provide them with shelter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/srila_guru_maharaja.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;srila_guru_maharaja.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Srila Bhakti Kusum Sraman Goswami Maharaja&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Image - Srila Bhakti Kusum Sraman Goswami Maharaja&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If any resident would come to complain about another  resident, Srila Maharaj would say “you are aatma, how come any words or deeds towards your body or mind would affect you?”, quoting “nainam chindanti sastrani…” His own response to external disturbances toward himself was to surrender to Sri Krishna and continue to chant Sri Harinama.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One resident had offended Srila Maharaja by cursing loudly using foul words. Maharaja was silent on this and continued his chanting. Noticing that Maharaja was not objecting or responding, this resident became louder and ultimately raised shoes toward Srila Maharaja. After three days, while the offender was maliciously engaged in  offensive talks with others, a ferocious snake fell on his head and bit him causing immediate death. Srila Maharaja prayed for forgiveness for and on behalf of the offender with a melted heart. This reminds us of Namacharya Sri Haridas Thakura.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What to speak of us, even heavenly demigods do not recognize a Vaishnava: “vaishnava cinite nare devera sakati”. We see an external appearance of a Vaishnava through our material senses and experiences. However only the Vaishnavas may  recognize each other.  The best of the Vaishnavas, Sri Shivji, had once sent in his own devotees, a shaiva couple, advising to accept shelter at the feet of Srila Sraman Goswami Maharaja. In another occasion, Shivji, Tarakeswar, had directed a person suffering from a disease, to get Srila Maharaja’s feet-water for his cure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Srila Bhakti Kusum Sraman Goswami Maharaja established Sri Giri Govardhan at Sri Chaitanya Math in Sri Mayapur to fulfill his Gurudeva’s desire and  paved the path around Sri Radhakund and Sri Shyamkund. He appeared on the day of Sri Govardhan puja and got bhajan-samadhi on the bank of Sri Radhakund in Sri Mayapur on Moksada ekadashi.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="life_stories" /><summary type="html">After graduating from Dhaka Mitford Medical School as a medical doctor, he came to Prabhupada Srila Sarasvati Thakura and received mantra diksa and Sri Harinama and started serving the devotees in Sri Mayapur as advised by his Gurudev.</summary></entry></feed>